VAISHALI PATEL Full Stack Developer Milpitas CA

Overall 4+ years of professional experience and computer science master with strong algorithmic, excellent programming, development and testing skills. Exceptional experience working on Full Stack, Automation testing of web and mobile application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Lang. : Python , Core Java, C#, JavaScript, Ajax, XML, Web API, Web Services (SOAP, REST)

Front-End : HTML, CSS, jQuery, JSON, XML, AJAX, React JS, Express JS, NodeJS

Database : Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB

Testing Tools & Fram : Selenium, Maven, Appium, Cucumber, TestNG, Junit, Sauce Labs, Postman

Misc Tools : Git, Gitlab, SVN, Jenkins, Jira, BugZilla, Firebug

IDE(S) : Eclipse Java EE, Android Studio, Xcode, VS code, Visual Studio

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Full Stack Web Development Jul 2022 to Dec 2022

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia, USA

Software development life cycle Jul 2015 to Dec 2015

eInfochips Training & Research Academy, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

M.Sc. in Computer Application Jun 2010 to May 2012

HNGU University, Patan, Gujarat, India

B.Sc. in Computer Application Jun 2007 to May 2010

HNGU University, Patan, Gujarat, India

PROJECT DETAILS

Veriti – MERN Stack Application for charities (donation to taxation)

- Design and developed MERN stack web application, Rest APIs, securely SignIn/SignUp with JWTAuth.
- Built responsive UI experience with **ReactJS**, CSS, **Tailwind**, jQuery and built password security using **Bcrypt**.
- Responsible adding data queries using GraphQL library for APIS and stored data into MongoDB.
- Developed module to generate the statement and tax reports for user and for payment checkout using Stripe.
- Manage code in **Github** repository and deployed application on **Heroku**.

Novelty – Full Stack Application to book swap your personal library

- Built UI responsive full stack application using HTML, CSS(Bulma), Javascript, ExpressJS, NodeJS
- Responsible for setting up Repository on GitHub, added MVC structure files and routes.
- Integrated Google API by AXIOS where user can add book details to their personal library through ISBN.
- Worked on Login/Logout functionality using session authentication.
- Responsible to seed user and book data in mysql databse using sequelize library.

What's For Dinner? - Meal Planner (recipes to pricing)

- Responsible for create folder structure, files and imported materialize CSS framework for this project.
- Used MealDB, Krogger api to populate recipes and shopping lists in modal dialog based on user search criteria.
- Added tooltip functionality on meal title. Also responsible for error handling functionality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Test Analyst Aug 2019 to Apr 2021

Infosys, CA, USA

- Automated web and mobile native Android and iOS application testing.
- Enhanced Hybrid test framework using Selenium Web Driver with JAVA for Web application testing.
- Performed Functional testing and Regression testing in production environments for web application.
- Worked with engineering service team for developing the continuous integration environment in **Jenkins**.
- Run regression runs for new builds, perform failure analysis and generate the status for project tracking.
- Responsible for setting up the infra and framework for Mobile application testing. (both android and iOS)
- Enhanced data driven Hybrid framework for iOS and Android using Appium java client library and XCUITest.
- Used UI automator viewer in Appium to inspect elements in mobile application for android and iOS.
- Integrated **Sauce Labs** with existing framework for parallel execution of test scripts on different browser.

Software Engineer Jan 2016 to Aug 2018

eInfochips Ltd, Ahmedabad, India

- Involved in requirement gathering, design, development, testing and implementation of the web application by following software development life cycle (SDLC).
- Built MVC web applications using code-first and database-first approach. Designed an entire framework to support Test Driven Development (TDD) by making use of dependency injection and repository pattern.
- Communicated with clients for design, requirements and queries. Wrote, updated and maintained specification, end-user documentation and operational procedures.
- Followed Agile SCRUM Developmental approach to deliver product release by SPRINT processes in an iterative and incremental approach (SCRUM).
- Debugged and resolved various defects during project support phase after the feature development.